<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<concept id="concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB"
                    xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>The OpenStack Operator's Tasks</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>In order to use <ph
                            conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> for monitoring your OpenStack services and servers, you must install and configure so-called agents:<ul>
                    <li>A Metrics Agent is required for monitoring your services and servers. </li>
                    <li>A Log Agent is required for collecting the log data that is generated for your services and servers.</li>
                </ul></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Monitoring </title>
            <p>The Metrics agent is responsible for querying metrics and sending them to the Monitoring Service for further processing.</p>
            <p
                conref="../../overview/monitor/c-monitoring.xml#concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB/Metrics_represent_self-descri_concept_conbody_section_3_p"/>
            <p
                conref="../../overview/monitor/c-monitoring.xml#concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB/The_concept_conbody_section_3_p"/>
            <ul
                    conref="../../overview/monitor/c-monitoring.xml#concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB/System_metrics_for_example_concept_conbody_section_3_ul">
                <li/>
            </ul>
            <p>Your individual agent configuration determines which metrics are
                available for monitoring your services and servers. For details
                on installing and configuring a Metrics Agent, refer to the
                SUSE OpenStack Cloud Deployment Guide.
                <!--taroth 2017: FIXME SOCM: add chapter and section title here, too-->
            </p>
            <p>As soon as an agent is available, you have access to the <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> monitoring features. You work with a graphical user interface that is seamlessly integrated into your cloud infrastructure. Based on OpenStack Horizon, the user interface enables access to all monitoring functionality and the resulting large-scale monitoring data. A comfortable dashboard visualizes the health and status of your cloud resources.</p>
            <p>
                <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> provides functions for alarm and notification management. <ph
                    conref="../../overview/monitor/c-monitoring.xml#concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB/Template-based_alarm_definiti_concept_conbody_section_4_p"/></p>
            <p>For details on the monitoring functions, refer to <xref
                    href="../../shared/monitor/c-monitor.xml"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Log Management</title>
            <p>The Log agent collects the log data from the services and
                servers and sends them to the Monitoring Service for further
                processing. For details on installing and configuring a Log
                Agent, refer to the SUSE OpenStack Cloud Deployment Guide.
                <!--taroth 2017: FIXME SOCM: add chapter and section title here, too-->
            </p>
            <p><ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> stores the log data in a central database. This forms the basis for visualizing the log data for the <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> users. Advanced data analysis and visualization of the log data is supported in a variety of charts, tables, and maps. Visualizations can easily be combined in dynamic dashboards that display changes to search queries in real time. </p>
            <p>Based on OpenStack Horizon, the customizable dashboards are seamlessly integrated into your cloud infrastructure. They enable user access to all log management functionality.</p>
            <p>GUI-based alarm and notification management is also supported for log data. Based on a template mechanism, you can configure alarms and notifications to monitor the number of critical log events over time. Compound alarms can be created to analyze more complex log events. This automation of log handling guarantees that you can identify problems in your their infrastructure early and find the root cause quickly.</p>
            <p>For details on the log management functions, refer to <xref href="../../shared/logging/c-osologging.xml"/>.</p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
