<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<concept id="concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB"
                    xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Overview</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p><ph conref="../product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> provides one convenient access point to your monitoring data. Use <uicontrol>Monitoring &gt; Overview</uicontrol> to keep track of your services and servers and quickly check their status. The overview also indicates any irregularities in the log data of the system components you are monitoring. </p>
                        <p>On the <uicontrol>Overview</uicontrol> page, you can:</p>
                        <ul>
                <li>
                    <p>View the status of your services, servers, and log data at a glance. As soon as you have defined an alarm for a service, a server, or log data, there is status information displayed on the <uicontrol>Overview</uicontrol> page. Different colors are used for the different statuses. This makes it is easy to instantly detect any problem. </p>
                    <p>For details on defining alarms, refer to <xref href="c-monitor-alarm.xml"
                            />. For details on the status information, refer to <xref href="c-monitor-statusinfo.xml"
                        />.</p>
                </li>
                                <li>
                                        <p>Access a preconfigured dashboard that visualizes your metrics data. Starting from this preconfigured dashboard, you can create your own dashboards for visualizing your monitoring data as required. For details, refer to <xref
                            href="c-monitor-grafana.xml"/>. </p>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                        <p>Access a preconfigured dashboard that visualizes your log data. Starting from this preconfigured dashboard, you can create your own dashboards for visualizing your log data as required. For details, refer to <xref
                            href="../logging/c-osolog-kibana.xml"/>.</p>
                                </li>
                        </ul>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
