<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB"
                    xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>A Monitoring as a Service solution must ensure high availability and scalability. It must guarantee protection against system downtimes and data loss. To minimize these risks and automatically respond to both increasing and decreasing data loads in large-scale computing environments, <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> should be installed in cluster mode.</p>
            <p>The basic concept of clustering involves making the <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> components and data available on multiple host machines, hereafter also referred to as nodes. These nodes are organized to work together as a single logical unit. They provide high availability and a higher level of scalability than can be obtained by installing <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> on a single node only. In case of a breakdown of an individual machine or irregularities in the operation of individual <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> components, all processes and data are redirected and the workload is redistributed within the cluster. Typically, the tenant user or system operator who monitors the quality of his services in the cloud experiences no or only a very limited failure.</p>
            <p>The following illustration provides an overview of the main components of a <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> cluster:</p>
            <fig>
                <image href="../../images/cluster-basic.png" alt="cluster-basic.png" width="550" height="289"/>
            </fig>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
