<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB"
            xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Uninstalling the <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> Agents</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>To uninstall a <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> Metrics Agent or a <ph
                conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> Log Agent, proceed as follows:</p>
            <ol
                            compact="no">
                <li>
                    <p>Log in to the Control Machine.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Open the configuration file of the Control Machine with your favorite editor. </p>
                    <p>Example:</p>
                    <codeblock>sudo vim /etc/ansible/hosts</codeblock>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Check that the hosts from which to uninstall an agent are configured correctly. Multiple instances of an agent are uninstalled if multiple hosts are specified in the file. </p>
                    <p>The IP address of the remote machines as well as the user name of the user who is to uninstall the agent must be specified. </p>
                    <note othertype="note">The user who uninstalls the agents must have access to the corresponding hosts. Access as a user with root privileges is required. </note>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>To run the uninstaller for one or multiple instances of a <ph
                            conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> Metrics Agent, execute the following command:</p>
                    <codeblock>ansible-playbook /opt/FJSVsvcmm/monasca-agent-uninstaller.yml</codeblock>
                    <p>To run the uninstaller for one or multiple instances of a <ph
                            conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> Log Agent, execute the following command:</p>
                    <codeblock>ansible-playbook /opt/FJSVsvcmm/monasca-log-agent-uninstaller.yml</codeblock>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>To remove the technical users that were used by <ph
                            conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        />, execute the following commands:</p>
                    <codeblock>userdel -r mon-agent
userdel -r mon-log-agent</codeblock>
                </li>
            </ol>
            <p>The agents and their dependencies are uninstalled: </p>
            <ul>
                <li>The agents are stopped.</li>
                <li>The corresponding services are removed (<codeph>monasca-agent</codeph> or <codeph>monasca-log-agent</codeph>).</li>
                <li>The agents' configuration files and the directories where they are located are removed.</li>
            </ul>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
