<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Configuring Index Patterns</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p><ph conref="../product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> enables the dynamic mapping of fields. After configuring an index pattern, the indices that match the pattern are automatically scanned to display the list of index fields. This guarantees that the fields are correctly visualized in the dashboard.</p>
            <p><ph conref="../product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> ships with a preconfigured index pattern that allows you to instantly explore your Elasticsearch indices when accessing the dashboard for the first time. You can create additional patterns to view and analyze specific sets of data. One or multiple patterns can be created per project. When you create additional patterns, you have to set one of them as the default.</p>
            <p>To configure an additional index pattern, use <uicontrol>Settings > Indices</uicontrol>. Click the index pattern that is displayed in the <uicontrol>Index Patterns</uicontrol> field on the left, and use the <uicontrol>Add New</uicontrol> option.</p>
            <p>Indices that match the pattern you define must exist in the Elasticsearch database, and they must contain data. For an index pattern, you specify the following elements:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p><uicontrol>Index contains time-based events</uicontrol>. It is recommended that this option is selected. This improves search performance by enabling searches only on those indices that contain data on time-based events. </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p><uicontrol>Use event times to create index names</uicontrol>. It is recommended that this option is selected. This improves search performance by enabling searches only on those indices that contain data in the time range you specify. </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p><uicontrol>Index pattern interval</uicontrol>. Select <codeph>Daily</codeph> as index pattern interval. Daily intervals are supported by the Monitoring Service.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p><uicontrol>Index name or pattern</uicontrol>. The pattern allows you to define dynamic index names. Static text in a pattern is denoted using brackets. Replace the predefined pattern (<codeph>[logstash-]*</codeph> or <codeph>[logstash-]YYYY.MM.DD</codeph>) as follows: </p>
                    <p>Replace <codeph>logstash-</codeph> by the project ID of the OpenStack project whose log data is to be visualized in the dashboard.</p>
                    <p>Replace <codeph>*</codeph> or <codeph>YYYY.MM.DD</codeph> by <codeph>YYYY-MM-DD</codeph> as naming pattern. This naming pattern is supported by the Monitoring Service. </p>
                    <p>Example: <codeph>[557aff4bf007473d84069aca202a1633-]YYYY-MM-DD</codeph></p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p><uicontrol>Time-field name</uicontrol>. Select <codeph>@timestamp</codeph> as time-field name. <codeph>@timestamp</codeph> matches the <codeph>YYYY-MM-DD</codeph> naming pattern.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p>The default index pattern is automatically loaded when you access the log management window. It is marked with an asterisk in front of the pattern name in the <uicontrol>Index Patterns</uicontrol> field at the top left corner of the <uicontrol>Settings</uicontrol> page. Select the pattern you want to set as the default from the <uicontrol>Index Patterns</uicontrol> field. The content of the log management window is instantly updated.</p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
