<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Configuring Index Patterns</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>Index patterns are used to identify the Elasticsearch index to run search and analytics against. They are also used to automatically configure the fields displayed in the log management dashboard.</p>
            <p><ph conref="../product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> enables dynamic mapping of fields. After configuring an index pattern, the indices that match the pattern are automatically scanned to display a list of the index fields. This guarantees that the fields are correctly visualized in the dashboard.</p>
            <p><ph conref="../product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> ships with a preconfigured index pattern that allows you to instantly explore your Elasticsearch indices when accessing the dashboard for the first time. </p>
            <p>You can create additional patterns to view and analyze different sets of data, if required. One or multiple patterns can be created per project. You can also create index patterns for different projects. When you create additional patterns, you have to set one of them as the default.</p>
            <p>To configure an additional index pattern, use ##Settings >  Indices tab > Add New##. Indices that match the pattern you define must exist in the Elasticsearch database. They must contain data.</p>
            <p>To select a pattern as the default, use ##Settings > Indices##.</p>
            <p>For an index pattern, you specify the following elements:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><uicontrol>Index contains time-based events</uicontrol>. It is recommended that this option is selected. This improves search performance by enabling searches only on those indices that contain data on time-based events. </li>
                <li><uicontrol>Use event times to create index names</uicontrol>. It is recommended that this option is selected. This improves search performance by enabling searches only on those indices that contain data in the time range you specify. </li>
                <li><uicontrol>Index pattern interval</uicontrol>. Select <codeph>Daily</codeph> as index pattern interval. Daily intervals are supported by the <ph
                        conref="../product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> Service.</li>
                <li>
                    <p><uicontrol>Index name or pattern</uicontrol>. The pattern allows you to define dynamic index names. Static text in a pattern is denoted using brackets. Replace the predefined pattern (<codeph>[logstash-]*</codeph> or <codeph>[logstash-]YYYY.MM.DD</codeph>) as follows: </p>
                    <p>Replace <codeph>logstash-</codeph> by the project ID of of the OpenStack project whose log data is to be visualized in the dashboard.</p>
                    <p>Replace <codeph>*</codeph> or <codeph>YYYY.MM.DD</codeph> by <codeph>YYYY-MM-DD</codeph> as naming pattern. This naming pattern is supported by the <ph
                            conref="../product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> Service. </p>
                    <p>Example: <codeph>[557aff4bf007473d84069aca202a1633-]YYYY-MM-DD</codeph></p>
                </li>
                <li><uicontrol>Time-field name</uicontrol>. Select <codeph>@timestamp</codeph> as time-field name. <codeph>@timestamp</codeph> matches the <codeph>YYYY-MM-DD</codeph> naming pattern.</li>
            </ul>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
