<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB"
                    xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Log Management</title>
    <conbody>
                <section>
            <p>For managing the log data of your services and the virtual and physical servers on which they are provisioned, <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> integrates with Kibana, an open source analytics and visualization platform. <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> uses Kibana as a front-end application to the log data held in the Elasticsearch database. </p>
            <p>Kibana allows you to easily understand large data volumes. Based on the data that is stored in Elasticsearch indices, you can perform advanced data analysis and visualize your log data in a variety of charts, tables, or maps. Changes to the Elasticsearch indices are displayed in <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> in real time.</p>
            <p>The log management features of <ph conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> include:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Features for searching, visualizing, and analyzing the log data.</li>
                <li>Alerting features for monitoring.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>In the following sections, you will find information on the log management window where you search, visualize, and analyze your log data, as well as details on how to use the alerting features.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Accessing <ph conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/></title>
            <p>For accessing <ph conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> and performing log management tasks, the following prerequisites must be fulfilled:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p>You must have access to the OpenStack platform as a user with the <codeph>admin</codeph> and the <codeph>cmm-user</codeph> role, or any other role that is authorized to use the <ph
                            conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> monitoring functions. Additional roles are optional. </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>You must be assigned to the OpenStack project you want to monitor.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p>Log in to the OpenStack platform with your user name and password. This allows you to access the OpenStack Horizon dashboard. The functions you can use in OpenStack Horizon depend on your access permissions. </p>
            <p>The <ph conref="../product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> functionality is available on the <uicontrol>Monitoring</uicontrol> tab. It provides access to the log data of all projects to which you are assigned. Before you start, select the project you want to work on. The <uicontrol>Log Management</uicontrol> option at the top border of the <uicontrol>Overview</uicontrol> page displays the log management window where you can work on the log data of the selected project. </p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
