<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB"
                    xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Accessing <ph conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/></title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
                        <p>As an application operator, you must fulfill the following prerequisites:</p>
                        <ul>
                                <li>You must be registered as an OpenStack user.</li>
                                <li>You must have access to the OpenStack platform as a user with the <codeph>monasca-user</codeph> role or any other role that is authorized to use the <ph
                                                conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> monitoring functions. Additional roles are optional. Contact your OpenStack operator for more information.</li>
                                <li>You must be assigned to the project you want to monitor.</li>
                        </ul>
                        <p>Log in to OpenStack Horizon using the user name and password provided as login information by OpenStack. The tabs and functions you can access in OpenStack Horizon depend on your access permissions. </p>
                        <p>For monitoring your services and virtual machines, you use the <ph
                                        conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> monitoring user interface which is integrated into OpenStack Horizon. The <ph
                                        conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> functionality is available on the <uicontrol>Monitoring</uicontrol> tab. It provides access to the monitoring data of the project to which you are assigned. If you are assigned to more than one project, select the project you want to work on from the drop-down menu at the top left of the dashboard. </p>
        </section>
                <section>
                        <title>Supported Web Browsers</title>
                        <p>To perform monitoring tasks, you must use one of the Web browsers that has been used for testing <ph
                                        conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>:</p>
                        <ul
                                conref="../../cmmoperator/install/c-cmmoprepare-pre.xml#concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB/Google_Chrome_50.0_concept_conbody_section_2_ul">
                                <li/>
                        </ul>
                </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
