<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB"
                    xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Installation</title>
    <conbody>
                <section>
                        <p>The installation of <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> comprises several steps. They are partially executed by the <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> operator, and partially by the OpenStack operator.</p>
                </section>
                <section>
                        <fig>
                                <image
                    alt="installation-type-overview.png" height="346"
                    href="../../images/installation-type-overview.png"
                    width="350"/>
                        </fig>
                        <p>The installation of <ph
                        conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> comprises the following steps: </p>
                        <ol>
                                <li>Preparing the installation environment - done by the OpenStack operator and the <ph
                                                conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> operator.</li>
                                <li>Configuring the Control Machine  - done by the OpenStack operator and the <ph
                                                conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> operator.</li>
                                <li>Installing the offline resources - done by the <ph
                                                conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> operator only. </li>
                                <li>Installing the OpenStack extensions required for the <ph
                                                conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> Service - done by the OpenStack operator only. </li>
                                <li>Installing the <ph
                                                conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> Service - done by the <ph
                                                conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> operator only.</li>
                        </ol>
                        <p>As an OpenStack operator, you also install and configure the agents you use for monitoring your OpenStack services. Your tenant users who have booked a virtual machine in OpenStack monitor their machine with libvirt. As an OpenStack operator, you have to make the required libvirt preparations for your tenant users. For details, refer to <xref
                                        href="../prepare/c-osopreparetu.xml"/>.</p>
                        <p><ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> ships with an installer that is based on Ansible. You use it for installing the OpenStack extensions and the required agents. </p>
                </section>
                <section>
                        <title>Recommended Installation Environment</title>
                        <p>The following installation environment is recommended:</p>
                        <fig>
                                <image
                    alt="ansible-installation-connection.png"
                    height="206"
                    href="../../images/ansible-installation-connection.png"
                        width="327"/>
                        </fig>
                        <ul>
                                <li>
                                        <p>By default, the <ph
                                                        conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                        /> operator installs the offline resources, the <ph
                                                        conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                        /> components, and the required agents on one host (<ph
                                                        conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                        /> host). To ensure high availability and improve scalability, <ph
                                                        conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> can also be clustered and installed on multiple hosts. This does not affect your tasks as an OpenStack operator.</p>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                        <p>As an OpenStack operator, you install the OpenStack extensions and the required agents for the OpenStack Keystone service and the OpenStack Horizon service. Depending on your OpenStack environment, Keystone and Horizon can either be installed on the same or on two separate hosts.</p>
                                        <p>You can install additional agents for monitoring additional OpenStack services as required.</p>
                                </li>
                        </ul>
                        <p>The installation of the <ph conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> components is managed from a so-called Control Machine.</p>
                </section>
        </conbody>
</concept>
