<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB"
            xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Overview</title>
    <conbody>
        <section
                id="provides_a_comfortable_statu_concept_conbody_section">
            <p id="provides_a_comfortable_statu_concept_conbody_section_p_1"><ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> provides a comfortable status overview of your virtual machines. Use <uicontrol>Monitoring > Overview</uicontrol> to view their status at a glance. </p>
            <p>The <uicontrol>Overview</uicontrol> page enables access to all available monitoring data. Use the options at the top border of the page to access preconfigured <ph
                    conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> metrics dashboards. You have to create your own dashboard that visualizes your monitoring data. For details, refer to <xref
                    href="c-tumon-grafana.xml"/>. </p>
            <p id="provides_a_comfortable_statu_concept_conbody_section_p_2"
                                        >As soon as you have defined an alarm for a virtual machine, there is status information displayed for it on the <uicontrol>Overview</uicontrol> page. For details on defining alarms, refer to <xref
                                        href="../../shared/monitor/c-osomon-alarm.xml"/>. </p>
                        <p>The color of the boxes indicates the status of the virtual machine:</p>
            <ul
                    id="A_service_or_server_in_a_gree_concept_conbody_section_ul_1">
                <li>A virtual machine in a green box indicates that it is up and running. There are alarms defined for it, but the defined thresholds have not yet been reached or exceeded.</li>
                <li>A virtual machine in a red box indicates that there is a severe problem that needs to be checked. One or multiple alarms defined for the virtual machine have been triggered. </li>
                <li>A virtual machine in a yellow box indicates a problem. One or multiple alarms have already been triggered, yet, the severity of these alarms is low.</li>
                <li>A virtual machine in a gray box indicates that alarms have been defined, yet, the monitoring data has not yet been collected and sent. </li>
            </ul>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
