<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB"
                xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Basic Usage Scenario</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p
                    conref="../../overview/monitor/c-monitoring.xml#concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB/The_basic_usage_scenario_of_s_concept_conbody_section_2_p"/>
            <fig>
                <image
                    align="left" alt="metricslogs.png" height="298"
                    href="../../images/metricslogs.png"
                    placement="break"
                    width="700"/>
            </fig>
                        <p
                                conref="../../shared/intro/c-usagescenario.xml#concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB/A_concept_conbody_section_p_2"/>
            <p>The <b>OpenStack operator</b> is a special application operator who is responsible for administrating and maintaining the underlying OpenStack platform. The monitoring and log management services of <ph
                                        conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> enable him to ensure the availability and quality of the platform. He uses <ph
                                        conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> for:</p>
                        <ul
                                conref="../../shared/intro/c-usagescenario.xml#concept_E8D43EB4494E41D2AB42D4A89396D1AB/Monitoring_physical_and_virtu_concept_conbody_section_p_4">
                                <li/>
                        </ul>
            <p>As the <b>Monitoring Service operator</b>, you are responsible for providing the monitoring and log management features to the application operators and the OpenStack operator. This enables the application operators and the OpenStack operator to focus on operation and the quality of their services and servers without having to carry out the tedious tasks implied by setting up and administrating their own monitoring software. You use the monitoring features yourself for ensuring the quality of <ph
                                        conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
        </section>
                <section><title>The Monitoring Service Operator's Tasks</title>As the Monitoring Service operator, you have the following responsibilities: <ul>
                                <li>Installation and setup of the Monitoring Service, thus providing the monitoring features to the application operators, and the monitoring and log management features to the OpenStack operator. </li>
                                <li>Installation of the Metrics Agent and Log Agent on the <ph
                                                conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> host. The agents are required for monitoring <ph
                                                conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        />.</li>
                                <li>Regular maintenance of the components and services <ph
                                                conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> consists of. </li>
                                <li>Backup of the <ph
                                                conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> databases, configuration files, and customized dashboards.</li>
                                <li>Monitoring of <ph
                                                conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> to ensure the <ph
                                                conref="../../shared/product-name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> quality. For monitoring, you use a graphical user interface that is seamlessly integrated into the cloud infrastructure. Based on OpenStack Horizon, the user interface visualizes the health and status of your cloud resources and enables user access to all monitoring and log management functionality.</li>
                        </ul><p>The tasks of the Monitoring Service operator and the OpenStack Operator can jointly be performed by one system operator. In this case, also refer to the <i>OpenStack Operator's Guide</i>.</p></section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
